Andrew Johnson

GitHub: https://github.com/Johnson2017-stack, Linked In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/

andrew-johnson-24aaa223a,

Email: Andrew.k.johnson228@gmail.com, Yakima Valley, Wa or Remote

Summary

I am striving to work with a team to build a full stack application. I have expertise in HTML, CSS, Node, EJS, and Javascript. I just built an app referencing a nasa api using EJS and Javascript, also my weather app in my GitHub is built with javascript using react and deployed with Netlify.

Skills:

EJS

HTML

CSS

Flex-box

Boot strap

JAVASCRIPT

React

Node

Rest Api's

Software development

UX/UI

Microsoft office

Excell

Education:

SkillSpire- Full stack MERN software development- Currently taking classes-scheduled to complete class with a certificate in august

Online

Bellevue,WA

Colorado Technical Institute-BS in computer science-2017-2017

Online

Aurora,CO

Art Institute of Seattle, 3 months: 2010

Physical Classes

Seattle, WA

High School Diploma Tumwater High School Tumwater, WA [graduation: 2010] — Diploma Received

Projects:

Git hub repo of my ToDo list app:

https://github.com/Johnson2017-stack/todo-list-app.git

The deployed app:

https://johnson2017-stack.github.io/todo-list-app/public

GitHub repo of a weather application I built while in classes at skillspire:

https://github.com/Johnson2017-stack/weather-app-react.git

The deployed weather app with netlify:

https://ornate-selkie-5e0b99.netlify.app

Github repo of a Nasa application referencing their APOD API:

https://github.com/Johnson2017-stack/NASA-Apod.git

Work History:

(2/2021-2023)

Baxter Construction, Water Tech, Yakima, WA 98901

- Helped manage job sites to ensure that they were up to the standards of OSHA and the company.
 - Worked on call for emergency Water losses.
- First responder on job site to stop water intrusion into houses and or buildings, also was required to extract said water from the building.
- Properly dried out building structures to their dry standards with drying equipment.

[2016-2018

Lead technician, Interstate restoration, Denver, CO

- I would look over anywhere from 5 -100 personnel on large scale demolition projects to ensure that proper PPE was being worn and the job site was up to safety standards of the company and OSHA.
- I would order demolition tools and other materials needed to complete the job.
- I would have to properly identify the water intrusion, the category of the water that intruded, and how much drying equipment I would need to dry the structure.

[2015-2016]

Construction foreman, superintendent in training, palace construction, Denver, CO

- Helped order building materials that were needed for the job site.
- looked over helpers and some third party venders to ensure that the project would be completed by the deadline provided by the customer. This could be up to 50 Personnel on a daily basis.
- I would be tasked to examine all areas that were under construction at the end of the project to ensure it was ready to turn over to the owner AKA "Punch Work".

[2014-2015]

Water Tech, Palace Construction, Denver, CO

- Helped manage job sites to ensure that they were up to standards for OSHA.
 - Worked on call for emergency Water losses.
- First responder on job site to stop water intrusion into houses and or buildings, also was required to extract said water from the building.
- Properly dried out building structures to their dry standards with drying equipment.